<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>http on Fred Wieser</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/_net/web/http/</link>
    <description>Recent content in http on Fred Wieser</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/notes/_net/web/http/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ihttpclientfactory</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/_net/web/http/ihttpclientfactory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 09:36:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/_net/web/http/ihttpclientfactory/</guid>
      
      <description>Problems with HttpClient HttpClient implements IDisposable, but when the object gets disposed of, the underlying socket is not immediately released. This can lead to socket exhaustion. When using a shared instances of HttpClient in long-running processes, the if instantiated as a singleton or static object, HttpClient will fail to handle DNS changes. Overview IHttpClientFactory offers these benefits:
Supports DI. Injected HttpClient instances are Scoped. A central location for naming and configuring HttpClient objects.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>httputility</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/_net/web/http/httputility/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 09:17:19 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/_net/web/http/httputility/</guid>
      
      <description>System.Web.HttpUtility Use to encode or decode URLs when building web applications.
To encode or decode values outside of a web application, use System.Net.WebUtility.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>httpclient</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/_net/web/http/httpclient/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 09:41:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/_net/web/http/httpclient/</guid>
      
      <description>HttpClient Object –&amp;gt; HttpMessageInvoker –&amp;gt; HttpClient
Sending HTTP requests and receiving HTTP responses via URI.
HttpClient is intended to be instantiated once per application. HttpClient works only on async methods for its long-running APIs. Every HttpClient instance uses its own connection pool. Thread Safety Warning: HttpClient is not thread safe. However, all HTTP verb methods, except Send(), are thread safe.
Flaw When the HttpClient object gets disposed of, the underlying socket is not immediately released, which can lead to a socket exhaustion problem.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
