<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>design on Fred Wieser</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/wieserpedia/_net/user-interfaces/winui-3/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in design on Fred Wieser</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/wieserpedia/_net/user-interfaces/winui-3/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>silhouettes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/wieserpedia/_net/user-interfaces/winui-3/design/silhouettes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 18:49:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/wieserpedia/_net/user-interfaces/winui-3/design/silhouettes/</guid>
      
      <description>App Silhouettes Common pattern of relationship between elements such as app layering, menus, navigation, commanding, and content areas.
Top Navigation silhouette NavigationView is used in content layer Navigation is on same row as commands
Menu Bar silhouette MenuBar used as the base layer along with a CommandBar
Left Navigation silhouette NavigationView on top of app&amp;rsquo;s base layer
Tab View silhouette TabView on app&amp;rsquo;s base layer</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>commanding</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/wieserpedia/_net/user-interfaces/winui-3/design/commanding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 17:19:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/wieserpedia/_net/user-interfaces/winui-3/design/commanding/</guid>
      
      <description>Overview Command elements are interactive UI elements that let users perform actions (send an email, delete an item, submit a form). Command interfaces are composed of common command elements, the command surfaces that host them, the interactions they support, and the experience they provide.
Command elements Buttons—trigger an immediate action Lists—present items in an interactive list or grid (drop-down list, list box, list view, grid view) Selection controls—select from a few options (CheckBox, RadioButton, toggle switch) Calendar, date and time pickers—view/modify date and time info (calendar date picker, calendar view, date picker, time picker) Predictive text entry—Provide suggestions as users type (AutoSuggestBox) Command surfaces App canvas (content area)</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
