<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>app lifecycle on Fred Wieser</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/wieserpedia/_net/user-interfaces/maui/app-lifecycle/</link>
    <description>Recent content in app lifecycle on Fred Wieser</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 13:28:13 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/wieserpedia/_net/user-interfaces/maui/app-lifecycle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>overview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/wieserpedia/_net/user-interfaces/maui/app-lifecycle/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 13:28:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/wieserpedia/_net/user-interfaces/maui/app-lifecycle/overview/</guid>
      
      <description>Overview .NET MAUI raises cross-platform lifecycle events on the Window class when the app transitions states.
State Transitions Begin State Event End State Running Deactivated Deactivated Deactivated Stopped Stopped Stopped Resumed Running Stopped Destorying Not running Not running Created, Activated Running Events Note: These events have different names on Android, iOS.
Event Raised when Action Created Native window created (but perhaps not yet visible) N/A Activated Window activated N/A Deactivated Window no longer focused N/A Stopped Window no longer visible Disconnect; cancel pending requests Resumed App resumes from being Stopped (never raised first time app launches) Subscribe to events; refresh content that&amp;rsquo;s visible on the page Destroying Native window is being destroyed Remove event subscriptions attached to the native window.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>platform lifecycle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/wieserpedia/_net/user-interfaces/maui/app-lifecycle/platform-lifecycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 19:43:58 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/wieserpedia/_net/user-interfaces/maui/app-lifecycle/platform-lifecycle/</guid>
      
      <description>Platform Lifecycle Events Namespace: Microsoft.Maui.LifecycleEvents
.NET MAUI uses delegates that are invoked in response to a platform lifecycle event being raised. You can create handlers for these delegates. Android Each delegate has an identically named extension method used to register a handler for that delegate.
Responding to Android Lifecycle Delegates Call ConfigureLifecycleEvents method on MauiAppBuilder object in CreateMauiApp method of MauiProgram class:
using Microsoft.Maui.LifecycleEvents; namespace PlatformLifecycleDemo { public static class MauiProgram { public static MauiApp CreateMauiApp() { var builder = MauiApp.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
