<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>routing on Fred Wieser</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/asp.net/fundamentals/routing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in routing on Fred Wieser</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/notes/asp.net/fundamentals/routing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>overview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/asp.net/fundamentals/routing/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/asp.net/fundamentals/routing/overview/</guid>
      
      <description>Abstract [Documentation] Routing is matching incoming HTTP requests and dispatching them to the app&amp;rsquo;s executable endpoints.
Endpoints are the app&amp;rsquo;s units of executable request-handling code.
Routing can be configured via controllers, Razor Pages, SignalR, gRPC services, middleware, and delegates &amp;amp; lambdas registered with routing.
Endpoints Endpoints handle requests and execute code to generate a response. They are defined in Program.cs.
Basic Routing Example var builder = WebApplication.CreateBuilder(args); var app = builder.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>routing middleware</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/asp.net/fundamentals/routing/routing-middleware/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/asp.net/fundamentals/routing/routing-middleware/</guid>
      
      <description>Overview UseRouting — adds route matching to the pipeline; looks at endpoints defined in the app and selects the best match.
UseRouting works by calling the SetEndpoint method to attach the endpoint to the current context. UseEndpoints — adds endpoint execution to the pipeline; runs the delegate associated with each the selected endpoint.
UseEndpoints is terminal when a match is found. UseEndpoints uses GetEndpoint to retrieve the endpoint and then invokes its RequestDelegate property.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>url matching</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/asp.net/fundamentals/routing/url-matching/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/asp.net/fundamentals/routing/url-matching/</guid>
      
      <description>Overview An incoming request comes in. Routing matches the incoming request to an endpoint:
It sets an Endpoint and routes values to a request feature on the HttpContext from the current request: HttpContext.GetEndpoint returns the endpoint HttpRequest.RouteValues returns the collection of route values URL matching is part of routing and operates in a configurable set of phases:
Process the URL path against a set of endpoints and their route templates; return a list of ALL matches</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
