<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>methods on Fred Wieser</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/_net/types/classes/methods/</link>
    <description>Recent content in methods on Fred Wieser</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/notes/_net/types/classes/methods/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>partial methods</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/_net/types/classes/methods/partial-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 18:24:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/_net/types/classes/methods/partial-methods/</guid>
      
      <description>Partial Methods A partial class or struct may contain a partial method.
One part of the class contains the signature of the method.
An implementation is defined in the same part or another part of the class.
If the implementation is not defined, the method, and all calls to it, are removed at compile time.
A partial method is not required to have an implementation if all of these are true:</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>extension methods</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/_net/types/classes/methods/extension-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 21:38:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/_net/types/classes/methods/extension-methods/</guid>
      
      <description>Extension Methods Extension methods extend existing types without creating a new derived type.
They are static methods, but they are called as if they were instance methods on the extended type.
Extension methods can also extend types that are sealed.
Binding An extension method with the same name and signature as an interface or class method will never be called.
The compiler will always bind to the interface or class method when there is a conflict.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>finalizers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/_net/types/classes/methods/finalizers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 21:10:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/_net/types/classes/methods/finalizers/</guid>
      
      <description>Finalizers Each type can have a single finalizer that is called by the runtime when resources need to be released.
They release unmanaged resources like windows, files, network connections, or mutexes controlled by the OS.
They are also known as destructors (not deconstructors) because they destroy objects in memory.
Finalizers do not take modifiers and they do not have parameters.
They cannot be defined in structs. They cannot be inherited or overloaded.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>local functions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/_net/types/classes/methods/local-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 20:27:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/_net/types/classes/methods/local-functions/</guid>
      
      <description>Local Functions Methods that are only accessible from within the containing method in which they are defined.
They can be declared and called from methods (especially iterator and async methods), constructors, property accessors, event accessors, anonymous methods, lambda expressions, finalizers, and other local functions.
Modifiers Local functions support the following modifiers:
async unsafe static A static local function cannot capture local variables or instance state. extern An external local function must be static.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>deconstructors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/_net/types/classes/methods/deconstructors/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 10:31:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/_net/types/classes/methods/deconstructors/</guid>
      
      <description>Deconstructors The special method Deconstruct() is used to deconstruct a type:
public class Person { private string last; private string first; public Person(string lastName, string firstName) { last = lastName; first = firstName; } public void Deconstruct(out string lname, out string fname) { lname = lastName; fname = firstName; } } Person bob = new() { &amp;#34;eli&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;smith&amp;#34; }; var (name1, name2) = eli; name1 // returns &amp;#34;eli&amp;#34; name2 // returns &amp;#34;smith&amp;#34; Overloaded Deconstructors Overload deconstructors to allow callers to discard certain fields of the type.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>indexers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/_net/types/classes/methods/indexers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 11:26:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/_net/types/classes/methods/indexers/</guid>
      
      <description>Indexers Indexers (indexed properties) are Properties that can be indexed into some collection of values.
They enable objects to be indexed like arrays.
The compiler generates an Item property and the appropriate accessor methods.
Creating The name of the member is this:
public class Person { // … public Person `this`[int index] { // The indexer. // Avoid auto-implemented properties with indexers: get { return Children[index]; } // The get and set accessors make this indexer read-write.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>constructors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/_net/types/classes/methods/constructors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 11:25:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/_net/types/classes/methods/constructors/</guid>
      
      <description>Constructors Whenever a Class or Struct is created, its constructor is called.
Instance Constructors public class Person { private string Last; private string First; // Instance constructors initialize an instance of a class and are not inherited in derived classes. // Constructors have the same name as the class and are usually at the bottom of the class: public Person(string lastName, string firstName) { Last = lastName; First = firstName; } } Constructors do not use return statements.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>methods</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/_net/types/classes/methods/methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 10:44:24 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/_net/types/classes/methods/methods/</guid>
      
      <description>Methods Methods are functions that belong to a type that execute statements.
They are actions that an object can perform, either on itself or on related objects.
They can be declared in a class, record, or struct.
There are 4 specialized categories of methods:
Constructor Statements herein execute when new() is used to instantiate a class. Property Statements herein execute when data is set or get. Properties encapsulate (and protect) fields.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
