<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tools and diagnostics on Fred Wieser</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/wieserpedia/_net/tools-and-diagnostics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tools and diagnostics on Fred Wieser</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/wieserpedia/_net/tools-and-diagnostics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>logging and tracing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/wieserpedia/_net/tools-and-diagnostics/logging-and-tracing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/wieserpedia/_net/tools-and-diagnostics/logging-and-tracing/</guid>
      
      <description>Overview [Documentation] These notes discuss the differences between logging and tracing and the differences between the many logging APIs available in .NET.
Logging vs. Tracing Both logging and tracing serve as a record of interesting events that occur while a program is running.
Logging is expected to be collected all the time and should have low overhead. Unstructured logging yields log entries that have free-form text content. Structured logging yields log entries with well-defined schema and can be encoded in different machine-readable formats.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>observability and telemetry</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/wieserpedia/_net/tools-and-diagnostics/observability-and-telemetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/wieserpedia/_net/tools-and-diagnostics/observability-and-telemetry/</guid>
      
      <description>Overview Observability is the ability to monitor and analyze telemetry about the state of each component in a distributed system, to observe changes in performance, and to diagnose why those changes occur.
Intended to be transparent to the primary operation and have an insignificant performance impact so that it may be used continuously. A combination of logs, metrics, and distributed tracing. Observability approaches in .NET:
Explicitly in code (via OpenTelemetry) Out of process via EventPipe Inside a process via a startup hook — a low-level hook that allows injecting managed code to run before the main application&amp;rsquo;s entry point These notes focus on approach #1 above.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>containerization</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/wieserpedia/_net/tools-and-diagnostics/containerization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 13:32:54 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/wieserpedia/_net/tools-and-diagnostics/containerization/</guid>
      
      <description>Configure Container Image Most configuration is handled through MSBuild properties. Exception: RUN commands require a Dockerfile.
ContainerBaseImage The image used as the basis for the image being created.
&amp;lt;PropertyGroup&amp;gt; &amp;lt;ContainerBaseImage&amp;gt;mcr.microsoft.com/_net/runtime:6.0&amp;lt;/ContainerBaseImage&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/PropertyGroup&amp;gt; Defaults:
If project is self-contained, the mcr.microsoft.com/_net/runtime-deps image is used. If project is an ASP.NET Core project, the mcr.microsoft.com/_net/aspnet image is used. Otherwise the mcr.microsoft.com/_net/runtime image is used. ContainerRuntimeIdentifier The OS and architecture used by the container of the ContainerBaseImage supports more than one platform.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
