<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>readings on Fred Wieser</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/readings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in readings on Fred Wieser</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/readings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>runaround</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/readings/runaround/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/readings/runaround/</guid>
      
      <description>Runaround Isaac Asimov
It was one of Gregory Powell&amp;rsquo;s favorite platitudes that nothing was to be gained from excitement, so when Mike Donovan came leaping down the stairs toward him, red hair matted with perspiration, Powell frowned.
&amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s wrong?&amp;rdquo; he said. &amp;ldquo;Break a fingernail?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Yaaaah,&amp;rdquo; snarled Donovan, feverishly. &amp;ldquo;What have you been doing in the sublevels all day?&amp;rdquo; He took a deep breath and blurted out, &amp;ldquo;Speedy never returned.&amp;rdquo;
Powell&amp;rsquo;s eyes widened momentarily and he stopped on the stairs; then he recovered and resumed his upward steps.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the four agreements</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/readings/the-four-agreements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/readings/the-four-agreements/</guid>
      
      <description>Overview This is a summary of The Four Agreements by Don Miguel Ruiz.
Notes on two of the sections are incomplete at this time.
The Toltec The Toltec were a society of scientists and artists in Mexico thousands of years ago. Toltecs means women and men of knowledge.
The Smokey Mirror 3,000 years ago, there was a medicine man in training. He slept and saw his own body while dreaming. He said, &amp;ldquo;I am made of light; I am made of stars.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the five dysfunctions of a team</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/readings/the-five-dysfunctions-of-a-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/readings/the-five-dysfunctions-of-a-team/</guid>
      
      <description>Overview This is a summary of The Five Dysfunctions of a Team by Patrick Lencioni. Summary by Natalia Rossingol.
Dysfunction 1: Absence of Trust Trust is the foundation of real teamwork. And so the first dysfunction is a failure on the part of team members to understand and open up to one another. And if that sounds touchy-feely, let me explain, because there is nothing soft about it. It is an absolutely critical part of building a team.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
